<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blog on</title><link>https://www.cloudhypervisor.org/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Blog on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:49:55 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.cloudhypervisor.org/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Cloud Hypervisor v43.0 Released!</title><link>https://www.cloudhypervisor.org/blog/cloud-hypervisor-v43.0-released/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 21:31:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.cloudhypervisor.org/blog/cloud-hypervisor-v43.0-released/</guid><description>This release has been tracked in our roadmap project as iteration v43.0. The following user visible changes have been made:
Live Migration over TCP Connections # Support has been added to enable direct live migration from two hosts via TCP connections. This supplements the existing support for migrating over a UNIX socket which can then be tunnelled as desired. The documentation has been updated. (#6850)
Notable Performance Improvements # The VIRTIO_RING_F_INDIRECT_DESC feature has been enabled for virtio-block devices.</description></item><item><title>Cloud Hypervisor v42.0 Released!</title><link>https://www.cloudhypervisor.org/blog/cloud-hypervisor-v42.0-released/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 09:20:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.cloudhypervisor.org/blog/cloud-hypervisor-v42.0-released/</guid><description>This release has been tracked in our roadmap project as iteration v42.0. The following user visible changes have been made:
SVE/SVE2 Support on AArch64 # The SVE and SVE2 feature bits are now propagated through to the guest on AArch64. (#6678, #6691)
Notable Bug Fixes # Reduce latency notification when rate limited (#6672) Fix virtio-console resizing (#6704) Fix resizing when console uses TTY (#6754) Avoid deadlock in PCI BAR reprogramming that can occur when adding a new virtio device to a VM that has been restored (#6775) Fix console resizing after VM restore (#6748) Fix memory resize error due to incorrect bounds checks (#6736) Sponsorships # During this release cycle a new VFIO CI worker has been provided by Crusoe Energy and a new ARM64 CI worker has been provided by Ubicloud.</description></item><item><title>Cloud Hypervisor v41.0 Released!</title><link>https://www.cloudhypervisor.org/blog/cloud-hypervisor-v41.0-released/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2024 12:17:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.cloudhypervisor.org/blog/cloud-hypervisor-v41.0-released/</guid><description>This release has been tracked in our roadmap project as iteration v41.0. The following user visible changes have been made:
Experimental &amp;ldquo;Pvmemcontrol&amp;rdquo; Support # VMM support has been added for this experimental functionality (requires currently out of tree Linux kernel patches) to allow guests to control its physical memory properties to allow optimisations and security features. (#6318, #6467)
Sandboxing With Landlock Support # Support for restricting the VMM process using the Linux kernel &amp;ldquo;Landlock&amp;rdquo; API has been added - this can be used to restrict the files (and the read/write permissions) that the VMM process can access.</description></item><item><title>Cloud Hypervisor v40.0 Released!</title><link>https://www.cloudhypervisor.org/blog/cloud-hypervisor-v40.0-released/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2024 11:12:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.cloudhypervisor.org/blog/cloud-hypervisor-v40.0-released/</guid><description>This release has been tracked in our roadmap project as iteration v40.0. The following user visible changes have been made:
Support for Restoring File Descriptor Backed Network Devices # It is now possible to pass file descriptors over the HTTP API (and using ch-remote) when restoring to update the file descriptors for network devices. This enables snapshot &amp;amp; restore functionality for guests using macvtap or other file descriptor backed network devices.</description></item><item><title>Cloud Hypervisor v39.0 Released!</title><link>https://www.cloudhypervisor.org/blog/cloud-hypervisor-v39.0-released/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2024 13:40:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.cloudhypervisor.org/blog/cloud-hypervisor-v39.0-released/</guid><description>This release has been tracked in our roadmap project as iteration v39.0. The following user visible changes have been made:
Variable Sizing of PCI Apertures for Segments # It is now possible to use --pci-segment to adjust the aperture size that devices 32-bit and 64-bit PCI device BARs will be allocated from. Previously the address space was equally distributed across all the segments which may leave insufficient space for devices that require a large 32-bit space.</description></item><item><title>Cloud Hypervisor v38.0 Released!</title><link>https://www.cloudhypervisor.org/blog/cloud-hypervisor-v38.0-released/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2024 18:20:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.cloudhypervisor.org/blog/cloud-hypervisor-v38.0-released/</guid><description>This release has been tracked in our roadmap project as iteration v38.0. The following user visible changes have been made:
Group Rate Limiter on Block Devices # Users now can throttle a group of block devices with the new --rate-limiter-group option. Details can be found from the I/O Throttling documentation
CPU Pinning Support for Block Device Worker Thread # Users now have the option to pin virt-queue threads for block devices to specific host cpus.</description></item><item><title>Cloud Hypervisor v37.0 Released!</title><link>https://www.cloudhypervisor.org/blog/cloud-hypervisor-v37.0-released/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2023 18:58:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.cloudhypervisor.org/blog/cloud-hypervisor-v37.0-released/</guid><description>This release has been tracked in our roadmap project as iteration v37.0. The following user visible changes have been made:
Long Term Support (LTS) Release # This release is a LTS release. Point releases for bug fixes will be made for the next 18 months; live migration and live upgrade will be supported between the point releases of the LTS.
Multiple PCI segments Support for 32-bit VFIO Devices # Now VFIO devices with 32-bit memory BARs can be attached to non-zero PCI segments on the guest, allowing users to have more 32-bit devices and assign such devices to appropriate NUMA nodes for better performance.</description></item><item><title>Cloud Hypervisor v36.0 Released!</title><link>https://www.cloudhypervisor.org/blog/cloud-hypervisor-v36.0-released/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2023 16:06:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.cloudhypervisor.org/blog/cloud-hypervisor-v36.0-released/</guid><description>This release has been tracked in our roadmap project as iteration v36.0. The following user visible changes have been made:
Command Line Changes # We switched back to use the clap crate to create our command line, since the argh crate is barely maintained. There were several syntax changes:
All --option value commands now are --option=value. The --disk DISK1 --disk DISK2 command now is --disk DISK1 DISK2. The -v -v -vcommand now is -vvv.</description></item><item><title>Cloud Hypervisor v35.0 Released!</title><link>https://www.cloudhypervisor.org/blog/cloud-hypervisor-v35.0-released/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2023 14:47:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.cloudhypervisor.org/blog/cloud-hypervisor-v35.0-released/</guid><description>This release has been tracked in our roadmap project as iteration v35.0. The following user visible changes have been made:
virtio-vsock Support for Linux Guest Kernel v6.3+ # Since kernel v6.3, a vsock packet can be included in a single descriptor, instead of being split over two descriptors. Our virtio-vsock implementation now support both situations.
User Specified Serial Number for virtio-block # A new option serial is added to the --block command that allows users to specify a serial number for block devices which will be guest visible.</description></item><item><title>Cloud Hypervisor v34.0 Released!</title><link>https://www.cloudhypervisor.org/blog/cloud-hypervisor-v34.0-released/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2023 16:44:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.cloudhypervisor.org/blog/cloud-hypervisor-v34.0-released/</guid><description>This release has been tracked in our roadmap project as iteration v34.0. The following user visible changes have been made:
Paravirtualised Panic Device Support # A new device has been added that can communicate when the guest kernel has panicked and share those details with the VMM. This is controlled with a new --pvpanic command line option and JSON API change equivalent. (#5526)
Improvements to VM Core Dump # Requesting to dump the guest memory as core dump will now transparently pause the VM if required; returning to the original state after.</description></item></channel></rss>