<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blog on</title><link>https://www.cloudhypervisor.org/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Blog on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:49:55 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.cloudhypervisor.org/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Cloud Hypervisor v27.0 Released!</title><link>https://www.cloudhypervisor.org/blog/cloud-hypervisor-v27.0-released/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2022 18:02:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.cloudhypervisor.org/blog/cloud-hypervisor-v27.0-released/</guid><description>This release has been tracked in our new roadmap project as iteration v27.0.
Community Engagement # A new mailing list has been created to support broader community discussions. Please consider subscribing; an announcement of a regular meeting will be announced via this list shortly.
Prebuilt Packages # Prebuilt packages are now available. Please see this document on how to install. These packages also include packages for the different firmware options available.</description></item><item><title>Cloud Hypervisor v26.0 Released!</title><link>https://www.cloudhypervisor.org/blog/cloud-hypervisor-v26.0-released/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2022 16:48:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.cloudhypervisor.org/blog/cloud-hypervisor-v26.0-released/</guid><description>This release has been tracked through the v26.0 project.
SMBIOS Improvements via --platform # --platform and the appropriate API structure has gained support for supplying OEM strings (primarily used to communicate metadata to systemd in the guest) (#4319, #4446) and support for specifying the UUID (#4389.)
Unified Binary MSHV and KVM Support # Support for both the MSHV and KVM hypervisors can be compiled into the same binary with the detection of the hypervisor to use made at runtime.</description></item><item><title>Cloud Hypervisor v25.0 Released!</title><link>https://www.cloudhypervisor.org/blog/cloud-hypervisor-v25.0-released/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 14:59:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.cloudhypervisor.org/blog/cloud-hypervisor-v25.0-released/</guid><description>This release has been tracked through the v25.0 project.
ch-remote Improvements # The ch-remote command has gained support for creating the VM from a JSON config and support for booting and deleting the VM from the VMM.
VM &amp;ldquo;Coredump&amp;rdquo; Support # Under the guest_debug feature flag it is now possible to extract the memory of the guest for use in debugging with e.g. the crash utility. (#4012)
Notable Bug Fixes # Always restore console mode on exit (#4249, #4248) Restore vCPUs in numerical order which fixes aarch64 snapshot/restore (#4244) Don&amp;rsquo;t try and configure IFF_RUNNING on TAP devices (#4279) Propagate configured queue size through to vhost-user backend (#4286) Always Program vCPU CPUID before running the vCPU to fix running on Linux 5.</description></item><item><title>Memory Management Techniques</title><link>https://www.cloudhypervisor.org/blog/memory-management-techniques/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.cloudhypervisor.org/blog/memory-management-techniques/</guid><description>Depending on the expectations around the workload running in a Virtual Machine (VM), as well as the agreement between a customer and an operator, multiple use cases related to memory management between host and guest arise and they can be addressed through different techniques.
Host Managed # This section is about how memory can be managed by the host, as it knows the VM is going to need more or less memory during its runtime.</description></item><item><title>Cloud Hypervisor v24.0 Released!</title><link>https://www.cloudhypervisor.org/blog/cloud-hypervisor-v24.0-released/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2022 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.cloudhypervisor.org/blog/cloud-hypervisor-v24.0-released/</guid><description>This release has been tracked through the v24.0 project.
Bypass Mode for virtio-iommu # virtio-iommu specification describes how a device can be attached by default to a bypass domain. This feature is particularly helpful for booting a VM with guest software which doesn&amp;rsquo;t support virtio-iommu but still need to access the device. Now that Cloud Hypervisor supports this feature, it can boot a VM with Rust Hypervisor Firmware or OVMF even if the virtio-block device exposing the disk image is placed behind a virtual IOMMU.</description></item><item><title>Achieving Bare Metal Performance Within a Virtual Machine</title><link>https://www.cloudhypervisor.org/blog/achieving-bare-metal-performance-within-a-virtual-machine/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2022 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.cloudhypervisor.org/blog/achieving-bare-metal-performance-within-a-virtual-machine/</guid><description>There are use cases for which a workload needs to access specific hardware such as accelerators, GPU or network adapters to maximise potential performance. And since these workloads run inside virtual machines (VM) for security reasons, the challenge is to make this hardware available from within the VM, but without degrading the performance that can be achieved from bare metal.
VFIO, the Ideal Choice # This is a mature framework allowing a PCI device to be bound to the vfio-pci driver instead of the default driver it is usually attached to.</description></item><item><title>Cloud Hypervisor v23.1 Released!</title><link>https://www.cloudhypervisor.org/blog/cloud-hypervisor-v23.1-released/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2022 14:24:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.cloudhypervisor.org/blog/cloud-hypervisor-v23.1-released/</guid><description>This is a bug fix release. The following issues have been addressed:
Add some missing seccomp rules Remove virtio-fs filesystem entries from config on removal Do not delete API socket on API server start (#4026) Reject virtio-mem resize if the guest doesn&amp;rsquo;t activate the device Fix OpenAPI naming of I/O throttling knobs Download # See the GitHub Release for the release assets.</description></item><item><title>Cloud Hypervisor v23.0 Released!</title><link>https://www.cloudhypervisor.org/blog/cloud-hypervisor-v23.0-released/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2022 08:42:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.cloudhypervisor.org/blog/cloud-hypervisor-v23.0-released/</guid><description>This release has been tracked through the v23.0 project.
vDPA Support # A vDPA device has a datapath that complies with the virtio specification but with a vendor specific control path. The addition of --vdpa and the REST API equivalent allows the use of these devices with Cloud Hypervisor.
Updated OS Support list # The list of officially supported and tested OS versions has been updated to include Ubuntu &amp;ldquo;jammy&amp;rdquo; 22.</description></item><item><title>Cloud Hypervisor v22.1 Released!</title><link>https://www.cloudhypervisor.org/blog/cloud-hypervisor-v22.1-released/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2022 09:09:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.cloudhypervisor.org/blog/cloud-hypervisor-v22.1-released/</guid><description>This is a bug fix release. The following issues have been addressed:
VFIO ioctl reordering to fix MSI on AMD platforms (#3827) Fix virtio-net control queue (#3829) Download # See the GitHub Release for the release assets.</description></item><item><title>Cloud Hypervisor v21.1 Released!</title><link>https://www.cloudhypervisor.org/blog/cloud-hypervisor-v21.1-released/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2022 09:08:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.cloudhypervisor.org/blog/cloud-hypervisor-v21.1-released/</guid><description>This is a bug fix release. The following issues have been addressed:
Missing openat() syscall from seccomp filter (#3609) Ensure MMIO/PIO exits complete before pausing (#3658) Support DWORD writes to MSI-X control register (#3714) VFIO ioctl reordering to fix MSI on AMD platforms (#3827) Fix virtio-net control queue (#3829) Download # See the GitHub Release for the release assets.</description></item></channel></rss>