<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cloud Hypervisor Team on</title><link>https://cloud-hypervisor.github.io/contributors/cloud-hypervisor-team/</link><description>Recent content in Cloud Hypervisor Team on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Oct 2021 15:36:27 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cloud-hypervisor.github.io/contributors/cloud-hypervisor-team/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Cloud Hypervisor v19.0 Released!</title><link>https://cloud-hypervisor.github.io/blog/cloud-hypervisor-v19.0-released/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Oct 2021 15:36:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cloud-hypervisor.github.io/blog/cloud-hypervisor-v19.0-released/</guid><description>This release has been tracked through the v19.0 project.
Improved PTY handling for serial and virtio-console # The PTY support for serial has been enhanced with improved buffering when the the PTY is not yet connected to. Using virtio-console with PTY now results in the console being resized if the PTY window is also resized.
PCI boot time optimisations # Multiple optimisations have been made to the PCI handling resulting in significant improvements in the boot time of the guest.</description></item><item><title>Cloud Hypervisor v18.0 Released!</title><link>https://cloud-hypervisor.github.io/blog/cloud-hypervisor-v18.0-released/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Sep 2021 14:31:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cloud-hypervisor.github.io/blog/cloud-hypervisor-v18.0-released/</guid><description>This release has been tracked through the v18.0 project.
Experimental User Device (vfio-user) support # Experimental support for running PCI devices in userspace via vfio-user has been included. This allows the use of the SPDK NVMe vfio-user controller with Cloud Hypervisor. This is enabled by --user-device on the command line.
Migration support for vhost-user devices # Devices exposed into the VM via vhost-user can now be migrated using the live migration support.</description></item><item><title>Cloud Hypervisor v17.0 Released!</title><link>https://cloud-hypervisor.github.io/blog/cloud-hypervisor-v17.0-released/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 16:31:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cloud-hypervisor.github.io/blog/cloud-hypervisor-v17.0-released/</guid><description>This release has been tracked through the v17.0 project.
ARM64 NUMA support using ACPI # The support for ACPI on ARM64 has been enhanced to include support for specifying a NUMA configuration using the existing control options.
Seccomp support for MSHV backend # The seccomp rules have now been extended to support running against the MSHV hypervisor backend.
Hotplug of macvtap devices # Hotplug of macvtap devices is now supported with the file descriptor for the network device if opened by the user and passed to the VMM.</description></item><item><title>Cloud Hypervisor v16.0 Released!</title><link>https://cloud-hypervisor.github.io/blog/cloud-hypervisor-v16.0-released/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 16:13:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cloud-hypervisor.github.io/blog/cloud-hypervisor-v16.0-released/</guid><description>This release has been tracked through the v16.0 project.
Improved live migration support # The live migration support inside Cloud Hypervisor has been improved with the addition of the tracking of dirty pages written by the VMM to complement the tracking of dirty pages made by the guest itself. Further the internal state of the VMM now is versioned which allows the safe migration of VMs from one version of the VMM to a newer one.</description></item><item><title>Cloud Hypervisor v15.0 Released!</title><link>https://cloud-hypervisor.github.io/blog/cloud-hypervisor-v15.0-released/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 15:27:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cloud-hypervisor.github.io/blog/cloud-hypervisor-v15.0-released/</guid><description>This release has been tracked through the v15.0 project.
Highlights for cloud-hypervisor version v15.0 include:
Version numbering and stability guarantees # This release is the first in a new version numbering scheme to represent that we believe Cloud Hypervisor is maturing and entering a period of stability. With this new release we are beginning our new stability guarantees:
The API (including command line options) will not be removed or changed in a breaking way without a minimum of 2 releases notice.</description></item><item><title>Cloud Hypervisor v0.14.1 Released!</title><link>https://cloud-hypervisor.github.io/blog/cloud-hypervisor-v0.14.1-released/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Mar 2021 16:11:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cloud-hypervisor.github.io/blog/cloud-hypervisor-v0.14.1-released/</guid><description>Bug fix release branched off the v0.14.0 release. The following bugs were fixed in this release:
CPU hotplug on Windows failed due to misreported CPU state information and the lack of HyperV CPUID bit enabled (#2437, #2449, #2436) A seccomp rule was missing that was triggered on CPU unplug (#2455) A bounds check in VIRTIO queue validation was erroneously generating DescriptorChainTooShort errors in certain circumstances (#2450, #2424) Download # See the GitHub Release for the release assets.</description></item><item><title>Cloud Hypervisor v0.14.0 Released!</title><link>https://cloud-hypervisor.github.io/blog/cloud-hypervisor-v0.14.0-released/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 12:01:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cloud-hypervisor.github.io/blog/cloud-hypervisor-v0.14.0-released/</guid><description>This release has been tracked through the 0.14.0 project.
Highlights for cloud-hypervisor version 0.14.0 include:
Structured event monitoring # A new option was added to the VMM --event-monitor which reports structured events (JSON) over a file or file descriptor at key events in the lifecycle of the VM. The list of events is limited at the moment but will be further extended over subsequent releases. The events exposed form part of the Cloud Hypervisor API surface.</description></item><item><title>Cloud Hypervisor v0.13.0 Released!</title><link>https://cloud-hypervisor.github.io/blog/cloud-hypervisor-v0.13.0-released/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2021 11:02:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cloud-hypervisor.github.io/blog/cloud-hypervisor-v0.13.0-released/</guid><description>This release has been tracked through the 0.13.0 project.
Highlights for cloud-hypervisor version 0.13.0 include:
Wider VFIO device support # It is now possible to use Cloud Hypervisor&amp;rsquo;s VFIO support to passthrough PCI devices that do not support MSI or MSI-X and instead rely on INTx interrupts. Most notably this widens the support to most NVIDIA cards with the proprietary drivers.
Improve huge page support # Through the addition of hugepage_size on --memory it is now possible to specify the desired size of the huge pages used when allocating the guest memory.</description></item><item><title>Cloud Hypervisor v0.12.0 Released!</title><link>https://cloud-hypervisor.github.io/blog/cloud-hypervisor-v0.12.0-released/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 18:56:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cloud-hypervisor.github.io/blog/cloud-hypervisor-v0.12.0-released/</guid><description>This release has been tracked through the 0.12.0 project.
Highlights for cloud-hypervisor version 0.12.0 include:
ARM64 enhancements # The use of --watchdog is now fully supported as is the ability to reboot the VM from within the guest when running Cloud Hypervisor on an ARM64 system.
Removal of vhost-user-net and vhost-user-block self spawning # In order to use vhost-user-net or vhost-user-block backends the user is now responsible for starting the backend and providing the socket for the VMM to use.</description></item><item><title>Cloud Hypervisor v0.11.0 Released!</title><link>https://cloud-hypervisor.github.io/blog/cloud-hypervisor-v0.11.0-released/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2020 17:55:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cloud-hypervisor.github.io/blog/cloud-hypervisor-v0.11.0-released/</guid><description>v0.11.0 # This release has been tracked through the 0.11.0 project.
Highlights for cloud-hypervisor version 0.11.0 include:
io_uring support by default for virtio-block # Provided that the host OS supports it (Linux kernel 5.8+) then io_uring will be used for a significantly higher performance block device.
Windows Guest Support # This is the first release where we officially support Windows running as a guest. Full details of how to setup the image and run Cloud Hypervisor with a Windows guest can be found in the dedicated Windows documentation.</description></item></channel></rss>