<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cloud Hypervisor Team on</title><link>https://www.cloudhypervisor.org/contributors/cloud-hypervisor-team/</link><description>Recent content in Cloud Hypervisor Team on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2023 14:47:24 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.cloudhypervisor.org/contributors/cloud-hypervisor-team/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Cloud Hypervisor v35.0 Released!</title><link>https://www.cloudhypervisor.org/blog/cloud-hypervisor-v35.0-released/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2023 14:47:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.cloudhypervisor.org/blog/cloud-hypervisor-v35.0-released/</guid><description>This release has been tracked in our roadmap project as iteration v35.0. The following user visible changes have been made:
virtio-vsock Support for Linux Guest Kernel v6.3+ # Since kernel v6.3, a vsock packet can be included in a single descriptor, instead of being split over two descriptors. Our virtio-vsock implementation now support both situations.
User Specified Serial Number for virtio-block # A new option serial is added to the --block command that allows users to specify a serial number for block devices which will be guest visible.</description></item><item><title>Cloud Hypervisor v34.0 Released!</title><link>https://www.cloudhypervisor.org/blog/cloud-hypervisor-v34.0-released/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2023 16:44:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.cloudhypervisor.org/blog/cloud-hypervisor-v34.0-released/</guid><description>This release has been tracked in our roadmap project as iteration v34.0. The following user visible changes have been made:
Paravirtualised Panic Device Support # A new device has been added that can communicate when the guest kernel has panicked and share those details with the VMM. This is controlled with a new --pvpanic command line option and JSON API change equivalent. (#5526)
Improvements to VM Core Dump # Requesting to dump the guest memory as core dump will now transparently pause the VM if required; returning to the original state after.</description></item><item><title>Cloud Hypervisor v33.0 Released!</title><link>https://www.cloudhypervisor.org/blog/cloud-hypervisor-v33.0-released/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jun 2023 17:32:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.cloudhypervisor.org/blog/cloud-hypervisor-v33.0-released/</guid><description>v33.0 # This release has been tracked in our roadmap project as iteration v33.0. The following user visible changes have been made:
D-Bus based API # A D-Bus based API has been added as an alternative to the existing REST API. This feature is gated by the dbus_api feature. Details can be found in the API documentation.
Expose Host CPU Cache Details for AArch64 # Now the CPU cache information on the host is properly exposed to the guest on AArch64.</description></item><item><title>Cloud Hypervisor v32.0 Released!</title><link>https://www.cloudhypervisor.org/blog/cloud-hypervisor-v32.0-released/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2023 18:13:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.cloudhypervisor.org/blog/cloud-hypervisor-v32.0-released/</guid><description>This release has been tracked in our roadmap project as iteration v32.0. The following user visible changes have been made:
Increased PCI Segment Limit # The maximum number of PCI segments that can be used is now 96 (up from 16).
API Changes # The VmmPingResponse now includes the PID as well as the build details. (#5348) Notable Bug Fixes # Ignore and warn TAP FDs sent via the HTTP request body (#5350) Properly preserve and close valid FDs for TAP devices (#5373) Only use KVM_ARM_VCPU_PMU_V3 if available (#5360) Only touch the tty flags if it&amp;rsquo;s being used (#5343) Fix seccomp filter lists for vhost-user devices (#5361) The number of vCPUs is capped at the hypervisor maximum (#5357) Fixes for TTY reset (#5414) CPU topology fixes on MSHV (#5325) Seccomp fixes for older distributions (#5397) Contributors # Many thanks to everyone who has contributed to our release:</description></item><item><title>Cloud Hypervisor v31.0 Released!</title><link>https://www.cloudhypervisor.org/blog/cloud-hypervisor-v31.0-released/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2023 14:47:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.cloudhypervisor.org/blog/cloud-hypervisor-v31.0-released/</guid><description>This release has been tracked in our roadmap project as iteration v31.0. The following user visible changes have been made:
Update to Latest acpi_tables # Adapted to the latest acpi_tables. There has been significant API changes in the crate.
Update Reference Kernel to 6.2 # Updated the recommended guest kernel version from 6.1.6 to 6.2.
Improvements on Console SIGWINCH Handler # A separate thread had been created to capture the SIGWINCH signal and resize the guest console.</description></item><item><title>Cloud Hypervisor v30.0 Released!</title><link>https://www.cloudhypervisor.org/blog/cloud-hypervisor-v30.0-released/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2023 01:10:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.cloudhypervisor.org/blog/cloud-hypervisor-v30.0-released/</guid><description>This release has been tracked in our roadmap project as iteration v30.0. The following user visible changes have been made:
Command Line Changes for Reduced Binary Size # The clap crate was replaced by the argh crate to create our command line, which reduced our release binary size from 3.6MB to 3.3MB. There were several syntax changes:
All --option=value commands now are --option value. The --disk DISK1 DISK2 command now is --disk DISK1 --disk DISK2.</description></item><item><title>Cloud Hypervisor v29.0 Released!</title><link>https://www.cloudhypervisor.org/blog/cloud-hypervisor-v29.0-released/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2023 12:46:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.cloudhypervisor.org/blog/cloud-hypervisor-v29.0-released/</guid><description>This release has been tracked in our roadmap project as iteration v29.0. The following user visible changes have been made:
Release Binary Supports Both MSHV and KVM # On x86-64 the binary included in releases supports both the KVM and MSHV hypervisor with runtime detection to identify the correct hypervisor to use.
Snapshot/Restore and Live Migration Improvements # Improvements have been made to the data structures used for both live migration and snapshot/restore.</description></item><item><title>Cloud Hypervisor v28.1 Released!</title><link>https://www.cloudhypervisor.org/blog/cloud-hypervisor-v28.1-released/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2022 11:20:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.cloudhypervisor.org/blog/cloud-hypervisor-v28.1-released/</guid><description>This is a bug fix release. The following issues have been addressed:
Update dependencies including a version of linux-loader that addresses an infinite loop issue (details) Fix bugs related to virtio-net including an integer overflow issue (#4924, #4949) Use host cpuid information for L2 cache for older KVM on x86 (#4920) Improve README and documentation Download # See the GitHub Release for the release assets.</description></item><item><title>Cloud Hypervisor v28.0 Released!</title><link>https://www.cloudhypervisor.org/blog/cloud-hypervisor-v28.0-released/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2022 16:59:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.cloudhypervisor.org/blog/cloud-hypervisor-v28.0-released/</guid><description>This release has been tracked in our new roadmap project as iteration v28.0.
Community Engagement (Reminder) # Just a reminder that we have a new mailing list to support broader community discussions. Please consider subscribing. We plan to use this to announce a regular meeting for those interested in talking about Cloud Hypervisor development.
Long Term Support (LTS) Release # This is the first version of Cloud Hypervisor to be released under the LTS release process.</description></item><item><title>Cloud Hypervisor v27.0 Released!</title><link>https://www.cloudhypervisor.org/blog/cloud-hypervisor-v27.0-released/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2022 18:02:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.cloudhypervisor.org/blog/cloud-hypervisor-v27.0-released/</guid><description>This release has been tracked in our new roadmap project as iteration v27.0.
Community Engagement # A new mailing list has been created to support broader community discussions. Please consider subscribing; an announcement of a regular meeting will be announced via this list shortly.
Prebuilt Packages # Prebuilt packages are now available. Please see this document on how to install. These packages also include packages for the different firmware options available.</description></item></channel></rss>