<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cloud Hypervisor Team on</title><link>https://www.cloudhypervisor.org/contributors/cloud-hypervisor-team/</link><description>Recent content in Cloud Hypervisor Team on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 05:36:56 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.cloudhypervisor.org/contributors/cloud-hypervisor-team/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Cloud Hypervisor v49.0 Released!</title><link>https://www.cloudhypervisor.org/blog/cloud-hypervisor-v49.0-released/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 05:36:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.cloudhypervisor.org/blog/cloud-hypervisor-v49.0-released/</guid><description>This release has been tracked in v49.0 group of our roadmap project.
MSHV Support Improvements # On AArch64 with MSHV, firmware boot (#7391) and graceful guest shutdown (#7354) are now supported, and CI coverage has been added (#7381).
Logging Improvements # Logs now use an improved timestamp format (#7355), emit an explicit message on graceful shutdown (#7346), and reduce noisy warnings with newer guest kernels (#7423).
Removed Default IP and Mask for virtio-net Devices # The implicit default IP (192.</description></item><item><title>Cloud Hypervisor v48.0 Released!</title><link>https://www.cloudhypervisor.org/blog/cloud-hypervisor-v48.0-released/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 23:05:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.cloudhypervisor.org/blog/cloud-hypervisor-v48.0-released/</guid><description>This release has been tracked in v48.0 group of our roadmap project.
Experimental fw_cfg Device Support # This feature enables passing configuration data and files, such as VM boot configurations (kernel, kernel cmdline, e820 memory map, and ACPI tables), from the host to the guest. (#7117)
Experimental ivshmem Device Support # Support for inter-VM shared memory has been added. For more information, please refer to the ivshmem documentation. (#6703)
Firmware Boot Support on riscv64 # In addition to direct kernel boot, firmware boot support has been added on riscv64 hosts.</description></item><item><title>Cloud Hypervisor v47.0 Released!</title><link>https://www.cloudhypervisor.org/blog/cloud-hypervisor-v47.0-released/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2025 22:48:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.cloudhypervisor.org/blog/cloud-hypervisor-v47.0-released/</guid><description>This release has been tracked in v47.0 group of our roadmap project.
Block Device Error Reporting to the Guest # Instead of exiting on I/O errors, the virtio-block device now reports errors to the guest using VIRTIO_BLK_S_IOERR. It improves the user experience particularly when the guest rootfs is not backed by the affected block device. (#7107)
Nice Error Messages on Exit # We now have the chain of errors being reported and printed nicely, when Cloud Hypervisor or ch-remote exits on errors.</description></item><item><title>Cloud Hypervisor v46.0 Released!</title><link>https://www.cloudhypervisor.org/blog/cloud-hypervisor-v46.0-released/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 22:07:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.cloudhypervisor.org/blog/cloud-hypervisor-v46.0-released/</guid><description>This release has been tracked in v46.0 group of our roadmap project.
File-level Locking Support with --disk # Now file-level locking is enforced for disk images, provided by users with --disk. This ensures that only a single Cloud Hypervisor instance can obtain write access to a given disk image at any time, preventing misconfiguration and avoiding potential data corruption. (#6974)
Improved Error Reporting with VM Resizing # Instead of returning a generic error 400 (e.</description></item><item><title>Cloud Hypervisor v45.0 Released!</title><link>https://www.cloudhypervisor.org/blog/cloud-hypervisor-v45.0-released/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2025 17:28:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.cloudhypervisor.org/blog/cloud-hypervisor-v45.0-released/</guid><description>This release has been tracked in v45.0 group of our roadmap project.
Experimental riscv64 Architecture Support # Cloud Hypervisor now has experimental riscv64 architecture support. Details can be found from the riscv documentation.
Alphabetically Sorted CLI Options # To improve the readability of CLI options, the output of the --help now is alphabetically sorted. (#6988)
Improved Downtime of VM Live Migration # The downtime of VM live migration is reduced via delaying some of the tearing down process of the source VM after the destination VM is up and running.</description></item><item><title>Cloud Hypervisor v44.0 Released!</title><link>https://www.cloudhypervisor.org/blog/cloud-hypervisor-v44.0-released/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 19:34:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.cloudhypervisor.org/blog/cloud-hypervisor-v44.0-released/</guid><description>v44.0 # This release has been tracked in our roadmap project as iteration v44.0. The following user visible changes have been made:
Configurable virtio-iommu Address Width # The iommu_address_width option has been added to --platform to allow users to limit the virtio-iommu address space in the guest. (#6900)
Notable Performance Improvements # The VIRTIO_BLK_F_SEG_MAX feature has been enabled for virtio-block devices, which brings significant performance improvements on throughput. (#6885)
The io_uring entries are no longer forced to use async helper workers, delegating the decision to the kernel.</description></item><item><title>Cloud Hypervisor v43.0 Released!</title><link>https://www.cloudhypervisor.org/blog/cloud-hypervisor-v43.0-released/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 21:31:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.cloudhypervisor.org/blog/cloud-hypervisor-v43.0-released/</guid><description>This release has been tracked in our roadmap project as iteration v43.0. The following user visible changes have been made:
Live Migration over TCP Connections # Support has been added to enable direct live migration from two hosts via TCP connections. This supplements the existing support for migrating over a UNIX socket which can then be tunnelled as desired. The documentation has been updated. (#6850)
Notable Performance Improvements # The VIRTIO_RING_F_INDIRECT_DESC feature has been enabled for virtio-block devices.</description></item><item><title>Cloud Hypervisor v42.0 Released!</title><link>https://www.cloudhypervisor.org/blog/cloud-hypervisor-v42.0-released/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 09:20:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.cloudhypervisor.org/blog/cloud-hypervisor-v42.0-released/</guid><description>This release has been tracked in our roadmap project as iteration v42.0. The following user visible changes have been made:
SVE/SVE2 Support on AArch64 # The SVE and SVE2 feature bits are now propagated through to the guest on AArch64. (#6678, #6691)
Notable Bug Fixes # Reduce latency notification when rate limited (#6672) Fix virtio-console resizing (#6704) Fix resizing when console uses TTY (#6754) Avoid deadlock in PCI BAR reprogramming that can occur when adding a new virtio device to a VM that has been restored (#6775) Fix console resizing after VM restore (#6748) Fix memory resize error due to incorrect bounds checks (#6736) Sponsorships # During this release cycle a new VFIO CI worker has been provided by Crusoe Energy and a new ARM64 CI worker has been provided by Ubicloud.</description></item><item><title>Cloud Hypervisor v41.0 Released!</title><link>https://www.cloudhypervisor.org/blog/cloud-hypervisor-v41.0-released/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2024 12:17:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.cloudhypervisor.org/blog/cloud-hypervisor-v41.0-released/</guid><description>This release has been tracked in our roadmap project as iteration v41.0. The following user visible changes have been made:
Experimental &amp;ldquo;Pvmemcontrol&amp;rdquo; Support # VMM support has been added for this experimental functionality (requires currently out of tree Linux kernel patches) to allow guests to control its physical memory properties to allow optimisations and security features. (#6318, #6467)
Sandboxing With Landlock Support # Support for restricting the VMM process using the Linux kernel &amp;ldquo;Landlock&amp;rdquo; API has been added - this can be used to restrict the files (and the read/write permissions) that the VMM process can access.</description></item><item><title>Cloud Hypervisor v40.0 Released!</title><link>https://www.cloudhypervisor.org/blog/cloud-hypervisor-v40.0-released/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2024 11:12:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.cloudhypervisor.org/blog/cloud-hypervisor-v40.0-released/</guid><description>This release has been tracked in our roadmap project as iteration v40.0. The following user visible changes have been made:
Support for Restoring File Descriptor Backed Network Devices # It is now possible to pass file descriptors over the HTTP API (and using ch-remote) when restoring to update the file descriptors for network devices. This enables snapshot &amp;amp; restore functionality for guests using macvtap or other file descriptor backed network devices.</description></item></channel></rss>